<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 5 Day Shenzhen Visa</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The 5 Day Shenzhen Visa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 12:34:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lets Go</title>
      <link>/lets-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 15:48:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lets-go/</guid>
      <description>Note: Since the end of March 2020 China has closed the all their borders for tourists. The 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa ist currently not available!  #Lets go to Shenzhen!
You can visit Shenzhen from Hong Kong without getting a visa in advance!
Visiting or living in Hong Kong and like to have short trip to Shenzhen, but you have no visa? Easy, you can simply go to the border and get a Shenzhen-only visa that is good for 5 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 13:10:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/</guid>
      <description>Note: Since the end of March 2020 China has closed the all their borders for tourists. The 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa ist currently not available!  How many days you can stay in Shenzhen with the 5 day Shenzhen visa? Can everybody get the 5 day Shenzhen visa? Can I use a new passport? Does everybody actually need a visa? What happen if entry gets refused? How about Australians? How about Americans? (USA passport holders) How about Philippine nationals which were in China before?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 12:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pages</title>
      <link>/page/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 22:54:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lok Ma Chau &amp; Shenzhen Bay</title>
      <link>/lok-ma-chau-sz-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 10:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lok-ma-chau-sz-bay/</guid>
      <description>Note: Since the end of March 2020 China has closed the all their borders for tourists. The 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa ist currently not available!  You can not get the 5-day Visa in Lok Ma Chau (Fútián / 福田) or Shenzhen Bay (Shēnzhèn wān / 深圳湾) border checkpoint! Don’t go there without visa! There are no other visa types available there. You will be send back to Hong Kong!
You can get them at Lowu and Huanggang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huánggǎng 皇岗</title>
      <link>/huanggang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 14:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/huanggang/</guid>
      <description>Note: Since the end of March 2020 China has closed the all their borders for tourists. The 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa ist currently not available!  Huánggǎng (皇岗) is a very popular border for buses and cars, and it is open 24 hours round the clock in both directions. Most of the buses from Mongkok, Wanchai etc. cross here. And you can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen visa here too!
Procedure:
 Firstly get off the bus at Hong Kong immigration, with all your luggage Go through the Hong Kong passport exit check, find your bus after you exit the building It’s another 1Km bus ride to the China immigration building Get off the bus, follow the flow of the people to the immigration hall The passport check is on the right hand side – but since you have no visa you go left to the sign saying Port Visa  Get the 5 day Shenzhen visa form and fill it  Hand it to the counter, and wait Waiting time is usually just a few Minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luōhú 罗湖</title>
      <link>/luohu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 14:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/luohu/</guid>
      <description>Note: Since the end of March 2020 China has closed the all their borders for tourists. The 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa ist currently not available!  The easiest border to cross into Shenzhen is probably Lowu (Luōhú/罗湖/羅湖). It can easily reached by MTR (subway), in fact, Lowu can only be reached by MTR from Hong Kong. The border is open from 06:30 in the morning until midnight 00:00. The visa office is open 07:00 to 23:30 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To…</title>
      <link>/general-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/general-information/</guid>
      <description>Note: Since the end of March 2020 China has closed the all their borders for tourists. The 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa ist currently not available!  Before you go, check this:
You have a passport, bring it
The passport must have at least one free page without any stamps
Your passport is not from one the following countries:
 India Indonesia Philippines South Africa Turkey  Special note, the above countries can not get the 5 day Shenzhen visa!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
