<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>covid on The 5 Day Shenzhen Visa</title>
    <link>/tags/covid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in covid on The 5 Day Shenzhen Visa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 12:34:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/covid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A No Update Update</title>
      <link>/a-no-update-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 12:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-no-update-update/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, a no update update. It’s September 2021 and the border is closed for most. This effects tourists, business visitors and most normal people, including all Hong Kong residents.
If you want to visit China you must apply a visa – even if you hold a valid multi-entry visa or an APEC card – a new visa must be applied. Depending where you enter you most likely get two week hotel quarantine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China closed to all foreigners!</title>
      <link>/china-closed-to-all-foreigners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 02:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/china-closed-to-all-foreigners/</guid>
      <description>From March 28th 2020 China will close its borders to all foreigners. Even if you hold a residence permit, that means, even if China is your home you can not return for the time being:
 In view of the rapid spread of COVID-19 across the world, China has decided to temporarily suspend the entry into China by foreign nationals holding visas or residence permits still valid to the time of this announcement, effective from 0 a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Virus Update!</title>
      <link>/corona-virus-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corona-virus-update/</guid>
      <description>Corona Virus Update!
Since the Lowu/Luohu und Huanggang land borders are closed, all ferry services are stopped and only the Shenzhen Bay border is open (this border has no 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa office) there is currently no way to get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa. And even if, from Saturday Feb 7th onward Hong Kong imposes a mandatory 14 days quarantine for anybody that arrives from China. People that had been to Hubei province in the last 14 days will be banned from entering.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
