<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The 5 Day Shenzhen Visa</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The 5 Day Shenzhen Visa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 12:34:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A No Update Update</title>
      <link>/a-no-update-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 12:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-no-update-update/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, a no update update. It’s September 2021 and the border is closed for most. This effects tourists, business visitors and most normal people, including all Hong Kong residents.
If you want to visit China you must apply a visa – even if you hold a valid multi-entry visa or an APEC card – a new visa must be applied. Depending where you enter you most likely get two week hotel quarantine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China closed to all foreigners!</title>
      <link>/china-closed-to-all-foreigners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 02:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/china-closed-to-all-foreigners/</guid>
      <description>From March 28th 2020 China will close its borders to all foreigners. Even if you hold a residence permit, that means, even if China is your home you can not return for the time being:
 In view of the rapid spread of COVID-19 across the world, China has decided to temporarily suspend the entry into China by foreign nationals holding visas or residence permits still valid to the time of this announcement, effective from 0 a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Virus Update!</title>
      <link>/corona-virus-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corona-virus-update/</guid>
      <description>Corona Virus Update!
Since the Lowu/Luohu und Huanggang land borders are closed, all ferry services are stopped and only the Shenzhen Bay border is open (this border has no 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa office) there is currently no way to get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa. And even if, from Saturday Feb 7th onward Hong Kong imposes a mandatory 14 days quarantine for anybody that arrives from China. People that had been to Hubei province in the last 14 days will be banned from entering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine – no border Visa for Women!</title>
      <link>/ukraine-no-border-visa-for-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ukraine-no-border-visa-for-women/</guid>
      <description>An update on my January 2019 post. About: no-female-Ukraine-passport holders: Unfortunately this rule is still valid and enforced (December 2019). Ukrainian women can not get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa at the border. No border Visa for Ukrainian women! User Nicolas had bad luck:
 Ahhhh. So nice. Why I didn’t find your comment before? Arrived after 22h long trip to HKG airport, went to Huanggang border by shuttle bus, they deny my Ukrainian girlfriend the 5 day Shenzhen visa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shenzhen Airport</title>
      <link>/shenzhen-airport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 08:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shenzhen-airport/</guid>
      <description>According to this website below you can get a visa on arrival (VOA) at the Shenzhen airport:
http://www.gdcrj.com/zxdt/zxdt/201507/t20150730_31301.htmThere are some requirements according the airline visa database:
`Passengers with a normal passport arriving at Chongqing (CKG), Guangzhou (CAN), Guilin (KWL), Haikou (HAK), Kunming (KMG), Qingdao (TAO), Sanya (SYX), Shenzhen (SZX), Weihai (WEH), Xi An (XIY) and Yantai (YNT) can obtain a visa on arrival if they have confirmation that a visa has been approved before departure and: that a visa will be issued on arrival; and passport contains at least 1 blank visa page for the sticker-type visa; and a sponsor (approved by Chinese authorities) meets passenger on arrival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine – Men only!</title>
      <link>/ukraine-men-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 08:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ukraine-men-only/</guid>
      <description>For Ukraine only men can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa, women can not!. The charge is RMB 409 (about US$ 60).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Africans – no visa!</title>
      <link>/south-africans-no-visa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 11:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/south-africans-no-visa/</guid>
      <description>South Africa passport holders can not get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa! Please don’t go to the border without visa!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forum added!</title>
      <link>/forum-added/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 13:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/forum-added/</guid>
      <description>To make it easier to find questions and comments I added a forum.
Feel free to comment or ask questions. It will be sorted later into categories if the topics are getting too mixed. Old comments might be added too. Enjoy!
 Sorry forum was discontinued and is closed now  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News for Indonesian passport holders – no more VOA currently</title>
      <link>/news-for-indonesian-passport-holders-no-more-voa-currently/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 02:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news-for-indonesian-passport-holders-no-more-voa-currently/</guid>
      <description>For Indonesians, sadly, nobody can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa. Before males could get it visa. Now all Indonesian passport holders can’t. Information dated: August 29th 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News: No China stamp okay again &#43; no Indonesian news</title>
      <link>/news-no-china-stamp-okay-again-no-indonesian-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 01:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news-no-china-stamp-okay-again-no-indonesian-news/</guid>
      <description>Some updates in July 2018:
I was told by a 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa staff that the ‘must have passport with China stamp‘ rule stopped. You can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa now with a new passport. My advice: bring your old passport with China stamp anyway if you have one. Rules can change all the time.
For Indonesians, sadly, there is no news. Males can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa, females can not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News: You need a passport picture!</title>
      <link>/news-you-need-a-passport-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 08:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news-you-need-a-passport-picture/</guid>
      <description>Another change at the border! You now need a passport picture when you apply for the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa. There is a photo booth just outside the visa office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News for Indonesians – must read, again!</title>
      <link>/news-for-indonesians-must-read-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 10:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news-for-indonesians-must-read-again/</guid>
      <description>I am sorry to post this, but the policy for Indonesians changed again!
Currently you can not get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa! You must get the full China visa before you go to the border.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News for USA</title>
      <link>/news-for-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 10:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news-for-usa/</guid>
      <description>It’s not exactly news, but since a few month USA passport can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa!
So far this is good news for US Americans!
However, the cost for them us RMB 956 – that is roughly US$ 150</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The French are fine now</title>
      <link>/french-fine-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 05:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/french-fine-now/</guid>
      <description>French passport holders can now make use the of 5-Days-Shenzhen-Visa. Cost is the regular RMB 168
Same rules apply, you need to have already a China stamp in your passport – if not no visa! If your passport is new and you have any old passport with a China stamp in it, bring it! That is acceptable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hong Kong visa office gets outsourced!</title>
      <link>/hong-kong-visa-office-gets-outsourced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 07:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hong-kong-visa-office-gets-outsourced/</guid>
      <description>According to the official Hong Kong China visa office in Wanchai they close to the public and outsource! business:
http://www.fmcoprc.gov.hkFrom now on the official visa please ist http://www.visaforchina.orglanding site, or http://bio.visaforchina.org/HKG2_EN/for Hong Kong.
Another option are travel agents, here is one that is also used by many to buy China visas:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not everybody needs a visa….</title>
      <link>/not-everybody-needs-visa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 13:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/not-everybody-needs-visa/</guid>
      <description>Not everybody needs a visa to enter China. There are a few nationalities that do not need a visa at all:
90 days visa free entry: San Marino
60 days: Mauritius
30 days: Bahamas, Barbados, Ecuador, Fiji, Grenada, Serbia, Seychelles, Tonga, UAE (after 16th January 2018)
15 days: Brunei, Japan, Singapore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News for Indonesians – must read!</title>
      <link>/news-indonesians-must-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 06:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news-indonesians-must-read/</guid>
      <description>Visitors from Indonesia are currently strangely treated when they apply for the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa – males can get the visa – females not!
Even for families that come in a group, husband and kids can get the visa – the wife not!
Some people suggested that this maybe related to Muslims (wearing headscarf or other Muslin dress) but this is not the case, it applies to all women from Indonesia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No more 5-day visa for 1st time visitors!</title>
      <link>/no-visa-1st-time-visitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 13:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/no-visa-1st-time-visitors/</guid>
      <description>There is a new regulation:
No more 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa for first time China visitors!
If your passport has no China visa in it from a previous visit you will not get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa.
If you have a new passport with no China chops, but have been China before you must bring your old passport if you want to get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How about the visa place next door?</title>
      <link>/visa-place-next-door/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 14:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/visa-place-next-door/</guid>
      <description>How about the visa place next door to the #ShenzhenVisa office in Lowu/Luohu?
No visa there currently. They did sell normal China visa (not the #ShenzhenVisa) in the past. But they have currently no visas at all. You can change money there, that’s it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesians can now get the #ShenzhenVisa (again)!</title>
      <link>/indonesians-can-now-get-shenzhenvisa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 08:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/indonesians-can-now-get-shenzhenvisa/</guid>
      <description>Rules have changed again at the Shenzhen Border and Indonesians can get the #ShenzhenVisa (again).
This rule has probably changed some time in January 2017,
You can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa at following borders Lowu, Huangang, Shekou and Fuyong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesians can not get the #ShenzhenVisa</title>
      <link>/indonesians-can-not-get-shenzhenvisa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 04:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/indonesians-can-not-get-shenzhenvisa/</guid>
      <description>February 2017 update: Rules have changes again at the Shenzhen Border and Indonesians can get the #ShenzhenVisa (again).
This post below is now obsolete:
Lately I see many Indonesians asking if they can get the 5-Day #ShenzhenVisa, or Shenzhen VOA – they can not!
Here is the list of nationalities that can not get the 5-Day #ShenzhenVisa :
The #ShenzhenVisa FAQ.
Reminder to those who can: You can not get the 5-Day #ShenzhenVisa at Shenzhen (Baoan) Airport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now on Twitter #ShenzhenVisa</title>
      <link>/now-twitter-shenzhenvisa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 08:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/now-twitter-shenzhenvisa/</guid>
      <description>We managed now to get on Twitter. Follow us for updates via #ShenzhenVisa !
You have any question about the 5-Day-#ShenzhenVisa ?
https://twitter.com/ShenzhenVisa or find us on Facebook!
https://www.facebook.com/5.Day.Shenzhen.visa/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your wait is over!</title>
      <link>/your-wait-is-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 08:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/your-wait-is-over/</guid>
      <description>We moved this website to a new, much faster, server. I need to watch the pages for the next few days. Not everything is working yet. If you see an error – send me a message!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Willkommen!</title>
      <link>/willkommen-in-shenzhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 16:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/willkommen-in-shenzhen/</guid>
      <description>I am just now trying to add German as 2nd language to the website. I guess the website will have some chaos for a few days.
Das richtige deutsch wird noch ein paar Tage dauern. Ich bitte um Vergebung!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Updates</title>
      <link>/some-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 09:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/some-updates/</guid>
      <description>My first blog entry, and a few updates from after I got online.
I recently tried Lok Ma Chau (Futian) and Shenzhen Bay border for the 5 Day Visa – both do not have it! Do not go there without visa!
Best way is either Lowu (Luohu) or Huanggang. Huanggang is open 24h, and the Port Visa Office is open 24h too. Huanggang is a bit harder to reach, must China buses cross there, or you can take Minibus #17 from Sheung Shui and get off at the ‘yellow bus station’, and take one of the yellow shuttles to the Hong Kong border (keep the ticket!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Shenzhen!</title>
      <link>/welcome-to-shenzhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 23:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/welcome-to-shenzhen/</guid>
      <description>You are visiting or living in Hong Kong and like to have short trip to Shenzhen, but you have no visa? Easy, you can simply go to the border and get a Shenzhen-only visa that is good for 5days.
 This website will tell you how. It’s easy when done the right way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
