<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>no entry on The 5 Day Shenzhen Visa</title>
    <link>/tags/no-entry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in no entry on The 5 Day Shenzhen Visa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 12:34:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/no-entry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A No Update Update</title>
      <link>/a-no-update-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 12:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-no-update-update/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, a no update update. It’s September 2021 and the border is closed for most. This effects tourists, business visitors and most normal people, including all Hong Kong residents.
If you want to visit China you must apply a visa – even if you hold a valid multi-entry visa or an APEC card – a new visa must be applied. Depending where you enter you most likely get two week hotel quarantine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China closed to all foreigners!</title>
      <link>/china-closed-to-all-foreigners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 02:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/china-closed-to-all-foreigners/</guid>
      <description>From March 28th 2020 China will close its borders to all foreigners. Even if you hold a residence permit, that means, even if China is your home you can not return for the time being:
 In view of the rapid spread of COVID-19 across the world, China has decided to temporarily suspend the entry into China by foreign nationals holding visas or residence permits still valid to the time of this announcement, effective from 0 a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Virus Update!</title>
      <link>/corona-virus-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/corona-virus-update/</guid>
      <description>Corona Virus Update!
Since the Lowu/Luohu und Huanggang land borders are closed, all ferry services are stopped and only the Shenzhen Bay border is open (this border has no 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa office) there is currently no way to get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa. And even if, from Saturday Feb 7th onward Hong Kong imposes a mandatory 14 days quarantine for anybody that arrives from China. People that had been to Hubei province in the last 14 days will be banned from entering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine – no border Visa for Women!</title>
      <link>/ukraine-no-border-visa-for-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ukraine-no-border-visa-for-women/</guid>
      <description>An update on my January 2019 post. About: no-female-Ukraine-passport holders: Unfortunately this rule is still valid and enforced (December 2019). Ukrainian women can not get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa at the border. No border Visa for Ukrainian women! User Nicolas had bad luck:
 Ahhhh. So nice. Why I didn’t find your comment before? Arrived after 22h long trip to HKG airport, went to Huanggang border by shuttle bus, they deny my Ukrainian girlfriend the 5 day Shenzhen visa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine – Men only!</title>
      <link>/ukraine-men-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 08:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ukraine-men-only/</guid>
      <description>For Ukraine only men can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa, women can not!. The charge is RMB 409 (about US$ 60).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Africans – no visa!</title>
      <link>/south-africans-no-visa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 11:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/south-africans-no-visa/</guid>
      <description>South Africa passport holders can not get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa! Please don’t go to the border without visa!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News for Indonesian passport holders – no more VOA currently</title>
      <link>/news-for-indonesian-passport-holders-no-more-voa-currently/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 02:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news-for-indonesian-passport-holders-no-more-voa-currently/</guid>
      <description>For Indonesians, sadly, nobody can get the 5-Day-Shenzhen-Visa. Before males could get it visa. Now all Indonesian passport holders can’t. Information dated: August 29th 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesians can not get the #ShenzhenVisa</title>
      <link>/indonesians-can-not-get-shenzhenvisa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 04:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/indonesians-can-not-get-shenzhenvisa/</guid>
      <description>February 2017 update: Rules have changes again at the Shenzhen Border and Indonesians can get the #ShenzhenVisa (again).
This post below is now obsolete:
Lately I see many Indonesians asking if they can get the 5-Day #ShenzhenVisa, or Shenzhen VOA – they can not!
Here is the list of nationalities that can not get the 5-Day #ShenzhenVisa :
The #ShenzhenVisa FAQ.
Reminder to those who can: You can not get the 5-Day #ShenzhenVisa at Shenzhen (Baoan) Airport.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
